RODRIGO DÍAZ SALVADORES

Industrial Design Engineer in Stockholm, Sweden

Forskarbacken 15, Stockholm · +34 633 019 977 · rodrigodiazsalvadores@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/rdsct

SKILLS

-.NET (C#, XAML) (2 years) - Adobe Photoshop (5 years) - Figma (2 years) - Adobe Illustrator (5 years) - Miro (2 years) - Adobe XD (1 year) - Sketch (1 year) - Adobe InDesign (4 years) - Jira (2 years)

NICE TO MEET YOU, INSURELLO!

I'm Rodrigo. I'm a recently graduated industrial design engineer at KTH in Stockholm. I have a strong passion for user-centered design in its many forms, in understanding user behavior and transforming it into something useful that hopefully creates an impact on people's lives. I have had the opportunity to show this in my more than five years of study and two years of experience at Thales.

EXPERIENCE

ELECTROLUX Stockholm, Sweden 01/2022 - Present

Student (Master Thesis)

- I develop a user-friendly process for repairing induction hobs to help fight obsolescence and early product replacement.

- The project involves a deep analysis of product attachment and its role in product and industrial design.
- Achievements: team collaboration, multidisciplinary research, conceptual product development, prototyping and UX/UI design in Figma.

KTH (KUNGLIGA TEKNISKA HÖGSKOLAN)

Stockholm, Sweden

08/2021 - 12/2021

- I helped teach the Adobe Suite programs to 100 students in their first year at KTH.
- The students were able to learn sketching and product visualization with Adobe Photoshop.
- Achievements: a consequent improvement of the teaching quality and performance.

THALES GROUP Madrid, Spain 02/2019 - 08/2020

.NET Developer

Teacher Assistant

- I created and developed 3 specific programs for the railway division of Thales.

- Using Microsoft .NET with C# for the backend, and WPF for the UI and frontend, prototyping in Figma.
- Achievements: improved efficiency of tasks that were done by hand, digitalization of the department.

EDUCATION

KTH (KUNGLIGA TEKNISKA HÖGSKOLAN)

Stockholm, Sweden Master's Degree in Integrated Product Design (GPA: 3.2/4.0) 08/2020 - 06/2022

UNIVERSITY OF ALCALÁ DE HENARES

Master's degree in Decision Making and Innovation (GPA: 3.4/4.0) 09/2019 - 05/2020

POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY OF MADRID

09/2015 - 05/2019 Bachelor of Science in Industrial Design and Product Development (GPA: 3.0/4.0)

RELEVANT PROJECTS

ELECTROLUX Stockholm, Sweden

Master Thesis: The perfect DIY repair experience

01/2022 - Present

Madrid, Spain

Madrid, Spain

- I designed a mobile app as the main pillar of a DIY repair experience for induction hobs, using Customer Journey Maps, user research and mockups with Figma.

PROJECT VERO Stockholm, Sweden

AR Glasses for a better online education

08/2020 - 01/2021

- I developed a service based on AR glasses that would enhance both student's and teacher's experience during the pandemic. See them in action here.